Edwin Kiplangat's Resume

Personal Information

Name: Edwin kiplangat

Phone NO: 0797569470

Email: kiplangatedwin91@gmail.com

Address: 00100 Nairobi

Professional summary

A motivated, adaptable and a flexible Information Technology enthusiast currently working

under the Presidential Digitalent program deployed as an Intern at Kenya Revenue Authority. I

am working in the Capacity and Availability department where we mainly monitor KRA systems

and networks. I have also one year working experience as an IT support at Circuit Business

systems, where I gained several crucial skills ranging from networking, computer maintenance,

installation and configuring both computer hardware and software. I also have got web

development skills having worked in this field as a freelancer mostly engaging in programming

languages such as Html, Css, Bootstrap, Javascript and Php and using figma for web design. I

have been engaged in developing several systems and currently I am developing a church

website which will be complete by the end of the month.

I am a goal-oriented person who is seeking exposure and more professional experience in this

field.

Portfolio: https://t.co/tBmHsVAfuS

Skills

• Data analytics (Excel and Tableau).

- Programming (Html, CSS, javascript, Bootsrap and Php).
- Systems and network monitoring using tools such as Nagios ,Nagvis and Grafana.
- Good use of windows and Linux operating systems.
- Troubleshooting of computer and network faults.
- IT support

Work History

December 2022 to current: Presidential Digitalent Program deployed as a Capacity and Availability Intern (Kenya Revenue Authority)

- Monitoring of KRA systems (e.g. ITAX, ICMS, TIMS and LOTUS) and networks using several monitoring tools such as Grafana, Nagvis, Packet lighter and Nagios.
- Configuration and deployment of monitoring agents in hosts such as routers and switches.
- Doing hourly, daily critical, weekly and monthly availability reports using tools such as Zabbix, Elastic and Grafana.

October 2021 to November 2022: IT Support Engineer (Circuit Business System)

- Installing and configuring operating systems, antivirus software and other applications such as Microsoft office.
- Installing and configuring hardware and software of Kiosks that dispense the queue tickets and lcd displays for various clients such as Absa bank, Safaricom and Ncba bank.
- Troubleshooting and offering support to the kiosks and lcd displays and also training the users on how to use them.
- Troubleshooting and fixing network, hardware and software related faults.
- Computer maintenance.
- Assisting in call center in receiving calls and attending to emails.

May 2021-August 2021: IT Security Attaché (Microlan Kenya Ltd)

- Handled the Sophos xg firewall
- I was tasked with the addition of clients and their devices to the Sophos endpoint security and control.
- Monitor network and application performance of various clients
- Generate reports and logs of various network and device activities of different clients.

Education

- 2017- 2021 : (Bachelor's degree in Computer Science) University of Embu attained 2nd class honors upper division.
- 2012-2016: (KCSE)Tumaini House School scored a B+
- 2004-2012: (KCPE) Kiptenden Primary School scored 357

Certifications and courses

- Google Ux design certification (Ongoing)
- Currently doing Huawei cloud and storage certification(ongoing)
- Google project management certification(completed).
- Sophos certified engineer(completed).
- Data analytics with Power Bi and Tableau course(Completed).
- NDG Linux Unhatched course(completed)
- Programming essentials in Python course(Completed).

Languages

Speak English, Kiswahili fluently

Interests/hobbies

Programming

Watching football.

Reading novels

1.Reference

Charles Chirchir Chief Executive Officer,

Microlan Kenya Limited.

Phone No: 0722411158

Email: Charles.chirchir@microlansolutions.com

2.Reference

DR. David Muchangi Mugo Chairman, Academic Leader and Lecturer, Department of Mathematics, Computing & IT, University of Embu

Phone No: +254 719 574060

Email: davemugo2005@yahoo.co.uk